Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- B Series Manuscripts. (Box 5-28)
  - B-759 Sixth Panzer Army (15 Dec. 1944-21 Jan. 1945). By SS Generalleutnant Walter Staudinger; 33 pp; 1948. The Ardennes offensive. (Box 26)
  - B-760 LXXXIX Corps (13 Oct.-23 Nov. 1944). By Oberst Otto Eckstein; 33 pp; 1948. In Lorraine. (Box 26)
  - B-761 Fifth Panzer Army Artillery (1-21 Mar. 1945) and Fifteenth Army Artillery (23 Nov. 1944-28 Feb. 1945). By Generalleutnant Karl Burdach; 26 pp, 5 illus; 1948. Of historical and technical interest. (Box 26)
  - B-762 LXXXVIII Corps (20 Mar.-10 May 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Heinz v. Prittwitz; 8 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 26)
  - B-763 Seventh Army (6 Jun.-29 Jul. 1944). By Generallieutnant Mat Pemsel; 172 pp, 29 illus; 1948. (Box 26)
  - B-765 LXXXIX Corps (20 Dec. 1944-13 Jan. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Kurt Reschke; 58 pp, 7 illus; 1948. Operation NORDWIND. (Box 26)
  - B-766 Nineteenth Army (16 Sep.-17 Nov. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 75 pp, 11 illus, 1948. Operations in Lorraine. (Box 26)
  - B-768 Panzer Lehr Division (15-25 Feb. 1945). By Major Helmut Hudel; 17 pp; 1948. On the left bank of the Rhine. (See also MS # B-830). (Box 26)
  - B-769 LXVI Corps (3-15 Jan. 1945). By General der Artillerie Walter Lucht; 10 pp; 1948. The Ardennes offensive. (Box 26)
  - B-770 79th Volks Grenadier Division (20-29 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Cord von Hobe; 6 pp. In the Palatinate. (Box 26)
  - B-771 212th Division (30 Mar.-2 Apr. 1945). By Oberst Cord von Hobe; 6 pp. (Box 26)
  - B-772* Panzer Kampfgroppe XIII (6 Apr.-5 May 1945). By Oberst Cord von Hobe; 36 pp. In Bavaria. (Box 26)
  - B-773 LXII Corps (10 Nov.-16 Dec. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Schack; 19pp, 4 illus; 1948. The Belfort Gap. (Box 26)
  - B-774 LXXXVIII Corps (1 Oct. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Heinz Prittwitz; 24 pp; 1947. Engagements in Holland. (Box 26)
  - B-776 Wehrmacht Classification Term's. By Major Helmut Hudel; 5 pp. (Box 26)
  - B-777 Remagen. By Guenther Kraft; 7 pp; 1946. The shooting of Major Kraft in consequence of the Remagen incident; an account by his son. (Box 26)
  - B-778 LXVI Corps (16-29 Jan. 1945). By General der Artillerie Walter Lucht; 8 pp; 1948. The last days of the Ardenn battle; historical data and critical comment. (Box 26)
  - B-780* XIII SS Corps (7 Nov. 1944-12 Jan 1945). By Oberst Kurt von Einem; 27 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Operations in Lorraine. (See also MS # C-039.) (Box 26)
  - B-781 Nineteenth Army (15 Sep.-18 Dec. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedr. Wiese; 22 pp, 5 illus; 1948. In and east of the Vosges Mountains (Alsace). (Box 26)
  - B-782 Army Group B Intelligence Estimate (6 Jun.-Jul. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Anton Staubwasser; 74 pp, 18 illus; 1947. Estimate of the enemy during the Normandy battle. (Box 26)
  - B-784 LXXXIV Corps (Jan.-17 Jun. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Friedrich von Criegern; 53 pp, 10 illus; 1948. In Normandy. (Box 26)
  - B-785* Remagen-Bonn Staff (1-7 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 18 pp; 1947. Remagen bridge; conditions west of the Rhine. (Not translated-1954). (Box 26)
  - B-786 First Army (20 Dec. 1944-10 Feb. 1945). By Oberst i.G. Albert Emmerich 24 pp; 1947. In northern Alsace. (Box 26)
  - B-787 Nineteenth Army (1 Jul.-15 Sep. 1944). By General der Infanterie Friedr. Wiese; 33 pp, 2 illus. Southern France; remarks of the army commander. (Box 27)
  - B-788 Fifth Panzer Army (25 Jan.-22 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Karl Wagener; 17 pp, 5 illus. Battles after the Ardennes offensive; historical data and comments. (Box 27)
  - B-789 The Defensive Battle. By Oberst Kurt Brandstaedter; 46 pp; 1948. A theoretical study base combat experience. Interesting examples from the operations of Nineteenth Army in Alsace, Jan.-Feb. 1945. Includes a short evaluation and critique by General der Artillerie Erich Brandenberger. (Box 27)
  - B-791a Tactical Air-Ground Cooperation. By Generalmajor Karl Heinrich Schultz; 35 pp; 1947. The prerequisites for tactical air support; organization and liaison on the basis of German methods and experience. (Box 27)
  - B-791b Ground Support Project # 42. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 5 pp, 2 illus; 1950. Air Signal Troops with Second Air Fleet (Italy), Of tactical and technical interest. (Box 27)
  - B-794 The 404th Division After 22 March 1945. By Generalleutnant Hermann Meyer-Rabingen; 22 pp; 1948. In Saxony during the last weeks of the war. (Box 27)
  - B-795 212th Division (1-28 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Max Ulich; 34 pp; 1948. (Box 27)
  - B-797 LIII Corps (27 Feb.-10 Mar. 1945). By Oberst i.G. Werner. Bodenstein; 22 pp, 5 illus; 1947. West of the Rhine. (Box 27)
  - B-798 LXVII Corps (15 Sep.- 25 Nov. 1944). By Oberst Elmar Warning, 58 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Between the Scheldt and Maas Rivers. Historical data and comment. (Box 27)
  - B-799 LXXXIX Corps (24 Jan.-8 Mar. 1945). By Oberstleutnant Kurt Reschke; 70 pp. Attack and defense in Alsace. (Box 27)
  - B-800 Army Group G (10 May-22 Sep. 1944). By Generaloberst Johannes Blaskowitz; 30 pp, 8 illus; 1947. In southern France; a survey of important events and decisions. (Box 27)
  - B-801 OB West-9 Questions (Jun. 1944-Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Bodo Zimmermann; 21 pp; 1947. (Box 27)
  - B-803 French Campaign (1940). By Generalfeldmarschall Wilhelm Ritter Von Leeb; 3 pp; 1946. (Box 27)
  - B-804 275 infantry Division (2-11 Nov. 1944). By Generalleutnant Hans Schmidt; 3 pp; 1945. Value of artillery preparation. (Box 27)
  - B-805 11th Panzer Division (Southern France). By Generalleutnant Wend von Wietersheim; 4 pp; 1945. (Box 27)
  - B-806 Fifteenth Army (Jun. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Adolf Kuntzen; 6 pp. Fifteenth Army situation estimate before and during the Normandy invasion. (Box 27)
  - B-807 LXXXI Corps (2 Aug.-4 Sep. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Ad. Kuntzen; 15 pp, 3 illus. In Normandy and northern France. (Box 27)
  - B-808 Franco-Italian Border Fortifications. By Hermann Wiery; 24 pp, 27 illus; 1947. Description and evaluation. (Box 27)
  - B-809 US Preparedness, German Estimate (1939). By General der Artillerie Friedrich von Boetticher, General der infanterie Kurt von Tippelskirch, and Generaloberst Franz Harder; 5 pp; 1947. Hitler's evaluation of the American war potential and strength in 1939. (Box 27)
  - B-812 Fifteenth Army (23-28 Feb. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav v. Zangen; 31 pp, 4 illus; 1948. In Holland and northern Germany. (Box 27)
  - B-813 Surrender in Italy (30 Apr.-2 May 1945). By General der Infanterie Friedr. Schulz; 5 pp; 1946. Of local historical interest. (English text not available in USAREUR.) (Box 27)
  - B-814 Panzer Operations (6-8 Jun. 1944). By Generalmajor der Waffen-SS Fritz Kraemer and Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 9 pp, 5 illus; 1948. Answers to a questionnaire on the commitment of armor against the Normandy landings. (Box 27)
  - B-815 Military Commander France-Functions. By Generalleutnant Dr. Hans Speidel; 6 pp; 1947. Policies and scope of responsibility as compared with German political agencies. (Box 27)
  - B-820 5th Parachute Division (6 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Gustav Wilke; 7 pp. In Normandy. (Box 27)
  - B-822 Measures Taken by the German Seventh Army in the Rear Area After the Breakthrough at Avranches. By Oberst Erich Helmdach; 17 pp; OCMH multillith; 1948. Normandy, 1-15 August 1944. (Box 27)
  - B-824 LXXIV Corps (May-10 Sep. 1944). By General der Infanterie Erich Straube; 46 pp; 1948. In Brittany and northern France; withdrawal to the West Wall. (Box 27)
  - B-825 Army Group B Intelligence Estimate (25 Jul.-16 Sep. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Anton Staubwasser; 157 pp, 26 illus; 1948. In northern France and Belgium; comments on German. Intelligence. (Box 27)
  - B-828 Fifteenth Army (1-9 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav von Zangen; 39 pp, 5 illus; 1948. Defense on the left wing; includes remarks on the Remagen bridge episode. (Box 27)
  - B-829 Fifteenth Army (9-12 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav von Zangen; 27 pp, 2 illus; 1948. Fighting for the Remagen bridgehead. (Box 27)
  - B-830 Panzer Lehr Division (25 Feb.-7 Mar. 1945). By Major Helmut Hudel; 13 pp; 1948. On the left bank of the Rhine. (See also MS # B-768.) (Box 27)
  - B-832 I SS Panzer Corps Artillery (6 Jun.-30 Jul. 1944). By SS Generalleutnant Walter Staudinger; 3 pp; 1948. In Normandy. (Box 27)
  - B-833 319th Infantry Division (1941-45). By Generalleutnant Rudolf Graf vol Schmettow; 69 pp; 1948. The Channel Islands before and during the invasion, up to the surrender on 9 May 1945. (Box 27)
  - B-834 Lower Rhine Fortifications (15 Sep. 1943-17 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Eckstein; 24 pp, 7 illus; 1946. Background to the strategic and tactical developments in autumn 1944. (Box 27)
  - B-835 Upper Rhine Fortifications (19 Oct. 1944-8 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Eckstein; 29 pp, 9 illus; 1947. Detailed report on construction work on the upper Rhine and in the Black Forest. (Box 27)
  - B-836 LIII Corps (8-16 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 27 pp; 1947. Fighting in the Ruhr pocket; an account based on a personal diary. (Box 27)
  - B-837 9th Panzer Division (24 Jul.-4 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Erwin Jolasse; 14 pp; 1948. In Normandy and northern France. (Box 27)
  - B-839 6th Parachute Regiment (1 May-20 Aug. 1944). By Oberst Frhr. Von der Heydte; 90 pp. In Normandy; commitment of a paratroop regiment as infantry. (Box 27)
  - B-840 Panzergruppe West (3 Jul.-9 Aug. 1944). By General der Panzertrupp Heinz Eberbach; 54 pp, 4 illus; 1948. In Normandy. (Box 27)
  - B-844 Kampfgruppe Keil (5-20 Jun. 1944) and 1058th Infantry Regiment (6- 8 Jun. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Guenther Keil; 22 pp. First days of the Normandy invasion. (Box 28)
  - B-845 709th Infantry Division (Dec. 1943-30 Jun. 1944). By Generalleutnart Karl-Wilhelm von Schlieben; 158 pp; 1948. Defense of Cherbourg; in part based on official war diaries. (Box 28)
  - B-847 Polish Campaign (1939). By Generalfeldmarschall Gerd von Rundstedt; 6 pp; 1948. Comments on organization and strategy. (Box 28)
  - B-849 Fifteenth Army (31 Mar.-15 Apr. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav von Zangen; 30 pp, 5 illus; 1948. In the Ruhr pocket. (Box 28)
  - B-850 Panzer Lehr Division (23 Mar.-15 Apr. 1945). By Major Helmut Hudel; 15 pp; 1948. East of the lower Rhine; fighting on the Sieg River and in the Ruhr pocket. (Box 28)
- C Series Manuscripts. (Box 28-30)
  The C-series was begun in July 1948, largely as a continuation of the B- and D-series. Studies which were intended as source material for writing the history of the U.S. Army in World War II have not been translated. PLEASE NOTE: Those manuscript numbers followed by an asterisk indicate publications that are NOT included on the National Archives' M1035 fiche. C-series manuscript titles are drawn from the Guide to Foreign Military Studies, 1945-54; Catalog & Index (Headquarters, United States Army, Europe, 1954)
  - C-001 6th Parachute Infantry Regiment in Action Against US Paratroopers in the Netherlands in Sep. 1944. By Oberst Freiherr von der Heydte; 11.pp, 4 illus 1948. (Box 28)
  - C-002 3d Panzer Grenadier Division (28 Dec. 1944-25 Jan. 1945). By Generalmajor. Walter Denkert; 22 pp, 2 illus; 194.8. In the Ardennes. (Box 28)
  - C-003 Defensive Combat of LXXXIX Corps in Lower Alsace and in the West Wall (6-31 Dec. 1944). By Oberstleutnant i. G. Kurt Reschke; 89 pp, 4 illus; 1948. (Box 28)
  - C-005 The Value of Documents as Source Material. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumerrtritt; 20 pp;1948. A critical study of the reliability of documents in writing military history. (Box 28)
  - C-006 Quotations in Military History. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 34 pp; 1948. The author questions the continuing validity of certain well-known statements by military and political leaders of the past. (Box 28)
  - C-007 Different Types of Armed Forces. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 29 pp; 1948. A historical survey of military organization. (Box 28)
  - C-009 Tactics and Operations. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 15 pp, 1 illus; 1948. An essay on the desirability of freedom for the independent and creative mind of the supreme commander. (Box 28)
  - C-010 347th Infantry Division (15 Nov. 1944-24 Mar. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wolf Trierenberg; 40 pp, 7 illus; 1948. In Lorraine and the Palatinate. (Box 28)
  - C-011 708th Infantry Division (1941-Aug. 1944). By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp; 21pp; 1948. Problems of coast defense at the mouth of the Gironde. (Box 28)
  - C-012 The Islands in the Bay of Biscay Between the Mouths of the Gironde and the Loire. By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp; 21 pp; 1948. The strategic and tactical importance of the islands of Noirmoutier, Yeu, Ré and Oleron in 1944 and their defenses. (Box 28)
  - C-020 The German Wehrmacht in the Last Days of the War (1 Jan.-7 May 1945). By Professor Dr. Percy E. Schramm; 674 pp; 11 illus; 1948. A partial reconstruction of the OKW war diary, based on original draft entries and. personal notes. The writer was official OKW historian. (Box 28)
  - C-021 Tactics of Russian Ground Support Aircraft. By Generalmajor Peter von der Groeben and General der Flieger Fritz Kless; 5 pp; 1948. Answers to a questionnaire. (Box 28)
  - C-022 Southern Part of Atlantic Wall. By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp; 29 pp; 1948. Between the Loire and the Pyrenees. (Box 28)
  - C-027 405th Infantry Division (Summer 1944-Spring 1945). By Generalleutnant Willy Seeger; 69 pp, 5 illus; 1948. On both banks of' the upper Rhine 1944-45. Includes operations in Alsace, the fall of Strasbourg, and fighting on the upper reaches of the Danube. (Box 28)
  - C-029 Secret Field Police. By Oberst Wilhelm Kirchbaum; 191pp, 13 illus; 1948. The development and history of the Geheime Feldpolizei as an army agency. The writer contends that it was not a National Socialist organization. (Box 28)
  - C-030 Russian Artillery in the Battle for Modlin and German Countermeasures. By General der Artillerie Wilhelm Berlin; 10 pp; 1948. Comments on MS# (Box 28)
  - C-032 The War Behind the Front: Guerilla Warfare. By Generalfeldmarschall Albert Kesselring; 42 pp, 2 illus; OCMH multilith; 1949. Guerilla warfare in Italy in 1944; countermeasures. A reliable study suggesting defects in the Hague Convention. Comments on the rules of land warfare. (Box 28)
  - C-033 Commitment of German Armor, 1943-45. By Generalleutnant Oldwig von Natzmer; 13 pp; 1948. German armored attack tactics; Russian antitank methods. (Box 28)
  - C-034 In Snow and Mud: 31 Days of Attack Under Seydlitz During Early Spring of 1942. By General der Infanferie Gustav Hoehne; 14 pp, 1 illus Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 5; 1953. Winter warfare in the East. Includes information about roads, reconnaissance, forest fighting, ski troops in the Demjansk area. (Box 28)
  - C-043 Eastern Nationals as Volunteers in the German Army. By Generalmajor Ralph von Heygendorf, Dr. Hans-Guenther Seraphim, and General der Kavallerie Ernst Koestring; 91 pp; 1949. Two essays based on the author's experiences a commanders of volunteer units, outlining methods of organization and command supplemented by a general statement by General Koesfring. (Box 29)
  - C-044 Certain German Military Terms. By the control group; 10 pp; 1948. Definition of the German use of the terms: strategy, operations, tactics, assignment. (Box 29)
  - C-048 I SS-Panzer Corps in the West, 1944. By Generalmajor Fritz Kraemer; 38 pp, 5 illus; 1949. A continuation of MS # C-024. (Box 29)
  - C-050 Conduct of Operations in the East, 1941-43. By General der Panzertruppen Walter Krueger; 20 pp; OCMH multilith; 1949. Organizational requirements for operations in Russia based on German experience. (Also included in Enclosure 18, MS # T-123.) (Box 29)
  - C-054 Experience Gained in Combined Arms Training with Live Ammunition. By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp, Oberst i. G. Herbert Koestlin, and Generalleutnant Willy Seeger; 121 pp, 20 illus; Hist Div USAREUR muftilith, Vol. II, No. 2; 1952. (Box 29)
  - C-055 Evaluation of Combat Infantry Experience. By Generalleutnant der Waffen-SS Max Simon; 29 pp, 20 illus; 1949. Views on the organization and armament of modern infantry, from the rifle squad to the regiment; desirability of the wedge formation in attack and defense. (Box 29)
  - C-056 Commentary on MS # B-418 (LXXXIV Corps in Normandy, 6 Jun.- 15 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Max Pemsel; 7 pp; 1949. Comments from the viewpoint of Seventh army. (Box 29)
  - C-057 Battle of Normandy-Comments (6-17 Jun. 1944). By Generalleutnant Max Pemsel; 15 pp; 1949. Comments on MS # B-784. (Box 29)
  - C-063 Austro-Hungarian General Staff. By General Albert de Bartha; 239 pp, 1 illus; 1951. Origin and organization of the Austro-Hungarian General Staff; its history through World War I; formation and history of the Hungarian General Staff to 1945. (Box 29)
  - C-064 Mediterranean War, Part V, "Campaign in Italy," Part II. By Generalfeldmarschall Albert Kesselring; 247 pp, 6 illus; 1950. Critique of MS # T-1b. Comments by the theater commander covering the period May 1944 to spring 1945. (Box 29)
  - C-064a Mediterranean War, Part V, "Campaign in Italy," Part II; to Commentary (a) and Questionnaire (b). By Generalfeldmarschall (Box 29)
  - C-064b Albert Kesselring; 2 vols, 21 pp; 1950-51. Authority and responsibility of the Commander in Chief Southwest in northern Italy. Includes a short supplementary questionnaire and comments on MS # C-064. (Box 29)
  - C-0651 Records of Situation Conferences of the National Defense Branch, Wehrmacht Operations Office (later Wehrmacht Operations Staff) 8 Aug. 1940-25 Jun. 1941. 270 pp, 1951. (Box 29)
  - C-065a Greiner Diary Notes, 12 Aug. 1942-12 Mar. 1943. 212 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065a GREINER SERIES-OKW WAR DIARY (1939-43). By Ministerialrat to im OKW-Dr. Helmuth Greiner; 1950-51 A day-by-day record of events at (Box 29)
  - C-065b OKW, World War II. 28 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065c Poland, 1939. 24 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065d Western and Northern Europe, 1940. 45 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065e Italy, Winter 1940-41. 34 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065f Africa, 1941. 44 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065g Balkans, 1941. 69 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065h Operation FELIX. 21 pp; 1950. 0-065i Operation BARBAROSSA. 126 pp; OCMH multilith; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065j Draft Entries in the War Diary of the National Defense Branch; Wehrmacht Operations Office (later Wehrmacht Operations Staff) Aug.-Nov. 1940. 222 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065k Draft Entries in the War Diary of the National Defense Branch, Wehmacht Operations Office (later Wehracht Operations Staff) Dec. 1940-Mar. 1941. 229 pp; 1950. (Box 29)
  - C-065m OKW until April 1943, compiled by the official OKW historian. A valuable record prepared from personal notes and original draft entries as a substitute for the original war diary destroyed at the end of the war. Describes Hiller's leadership, his reactions and decisions, and presents an overall picture of events as seen from the Wehrmacht Operations Staff. The work is divided into thirteen parts as follows: (Box 29)
  - C-065m Sheets from the War Diary of the National Defense Branch, Wehrmacht Operations Office (later Wehrmacht Operations Staff) 25, 27 Sep., 8 Nov. 1939, 23 Jul. 1941. 10 pp; 1950. Pages removed from the war diary by order of General Warlimont in order to conceal certain entries from Hitler. (Box 29)
  - C-067a Decisions Affecting the Campaign in Russia (1941-42). By to Generaloberst Halder; 2 vols, 26 pp; OCMH multilith; 1949. Answers to (Box 29)
  - C-067b three groups of questions on factors which influenced decisions of the German High Command in 1941-42. (Box 29)
  - C-075 Final Commentaries on the Campaign in North Africa, 1941-4. By to Generalfeldmarschall Albert Kesselring; 2 vols, 164 pp; 1950-51. A (Box 29)
  - C-075b critique of MS # T-3. Includes answers to three questionnaires on North Africa. (Box 29)
  - C-70 Reflections on High Command Organization-The Unification Problem. By General der Artillerie Walter Warlimont; 51 pp, 2 illus; OCMH lithograph, German Report Series; 1950. Based on the author's experience as OKW deputy chief of operations. (Box 29)
  - C-078 Sixth Army, Russia. By Major Francke; 74 pp, 3 illus; 1950. Defense and counterattack on the Mius Front, July-August 1943. A detailed account of an important battle won against heavy odds. Suited for use by service schools as an example of combat in Russia. (Box 30)
  - C-079 Experiences of a Division in Russia, 1941. By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp; 42 pp, 7 illus; 1951. Tactical examples illustrated by sketch maps. (Box 30)
  - C-080 Experience of a Battalion Commander on the Eastern Front. Author unknown; 10 pp; 1950. Translated from an article in "Allgemeine Schweizerische Miitaerzeitschrift," Vol. 2, February 1949. (Box 30)
  - C-095 War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Liaison Activities with Italian Sixth Army (1943). (Box 30)
  - C-095 WAR DIARY OF THE ITLIAN CAMPAIGN (1943-45). By General to der Panzertruppen Frido von Senger und Etterlin; 8 vols, 499 pp; 1951- (Box 30)
  - C-095a War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Sardinia and Corsica. (Box 30)
  - C-095b War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Cassino. (Box 30)
  - C-095c War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Prevention of an Enemy Breakthrough During the Retreat to the Arno. (Box 30)
  - C-095d War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Defense of the Gothic Line and Partisan Warfare Around Bologna. (Box 30)
  - C-095e War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Destruction of Army Group C. (Box 30)
  - C-095f War Diary of the Italian Campaign-Formal Surrender of Army Group C at Florence. (Box 30)
  - C-095g 53. Based partly on the war diary of XIV Panzer Corps, which the author. commanded, and partly on private diaries. The work is divided into eight parts as follows: (Box 30)
  - C-095g War Diary of the Italian Campaign-The End of the Hitler Regime. (Box 30)
  - C-101* The Relationship Between the German Campaign in the Balkans and the Invasion of Russia. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand; 25 pp; 1952. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 30)
- D-Series Manuscripts. (Box 30-34)
  The first studies in this series, MSS# D-001 through D-317, were written at Garmisch between December 1946 and July 1947. Later studies were answers to specific questionnaires submitted by OCMH. The last manuscript number was assigned early in 1951. Most studies in this series concern German operations in the Mediterranean theater and Russia, but there are also reports and theoretical treatises on naval and air warfare, strategy, tactics, organization, and operational problems of higher headquarters. As a group, the D-series studies are more hastily written and perhaps less reliable than studies in the C- and P-series. Some of these manuscripts have been used as source material for the T-series. PLEASE NOTE: Those manuscript numbers followed by an asterisk indicate publications that are NOT included on the National Archives' M1035 fiche. D-series manuscript titles are drawn from the Guide to Foreign Military Studies, 1945-54; Catalog & Index (Headquarters, United States Army, Europe, 1954)
  - D-002 Administrative Supply of the Luftwaffe in Africa and Italy. By Generalintendant Dr. Plogemann; 11 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Administration of rations, clothing, and pay. (Box 30)
  - D-003 Italian War Production Subsequent to 13 Sep. 1943. By Generalmajor Dr. Leyers; 39 pp, 1 illus, OCMH multilith; 1947. Illustrates problems of collaboration between allies. (Box 30)